nysun.com 2008-12-18

# Privacy Policy - The New York Sun

| 

  * **Privacy Policy**

At The New York Sun, we know how our customers and visitors like you value your privacy, and we have created this privacy policy to ensure that you understand our policies and procedures, what personal information we may collect and, ultimately, just how we use such personal information.

**Information Collected By The New York Sun**

The New York Sun collects two types of information from users of this website and the services offered on this Site (collectively, the "Site"): personal information described below; and non-personal information such as information about traffic patterns on the Site (for example, how many users log on to the Site on a daily basis).

**Personal Information**

You are not required to submit personal information to browse this Site. However, should you wish to subscribe to The New York Sun, you may order your subscription online through this Site, in which case we will request some personal information (such as your name, postal address and email address) and financial information (such as your credit card number and its expiration date) to process your subscription. Contact information from your order form may be used to fulfill subscriptions, to get in touch with you when necessary regarding your order and for other purposes, such as to provide information about our company to you. Credit card information that is collected is used to process your subscription, and will not be shared with third parties who are not involved with the transaction (but we may share non-credit card, non-personal information, such as information about which purchases you select, with third parties not involved in fulfilling your orders). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to secure and protect the privacy of your information.

In addition, should you choose to enter or respond to a contest, survey, sweepstakes or other promotional feature, we may ask you for your name, address and email address or other personal information. We will also collect any additional information or materials that you voluntarily provide to us (for further information, please see the Proprietary Rights to Content Section of our Terms of Use.

**How We Use Your Personal Information**

The New York Sun uses the information collected, including personally identifiable information, for a variety of purposes. For example, we use your information to better understand your needs and provide you with better news products and services. We may use your information to communicate back to you, to update you on our newspaper, services and benefits, to personalize the Site for you, to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information, newsletters, or other information on behalf of ourselves or third parties that we think would be of particular interest. We will always give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such materials.

We may also share your personal information with our affiliates, consultants, distributors, newspaper vendors, third party auditors and other third parties who make the Site or our newspaper available, enhance the Site's functionality or provide associated services who deal with you in processing your orders and/or delivering content, samples, products, services and gifts and prizes. Please note that we reserve the right to transfer your personally identifiable information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers of Site assets.

Information obtained through the Site may be intermingled with and used in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the Site, including both offline and online sources.

**Non-Personal Data**

In some cases, we may collect non-personal information. Examples of this type of information include the type of Internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system application software, and peripherals you are using and the domain name of the web site from which you linked to our Site. We use your information on an aggregated basis to do such things as operate our site, enhance our Site and sell and deliver advertising. We may share non-personal information with third parties for advertising, promotional and other purposes.

**Cookies**

We reserve the right to utilize cookie technology. A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain various types of information, including a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. We may use cookies to enhance your experience on this Site, to determine user traffic patterns and for other purposes.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies; however, you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent or you can flush your browser of cookies from time to time. (Note: you may need to consult the help area of your browser application for instructions.) If you choose to disable your cookies setting or refuse to accept a cookie, however, you may not be able to fully access and/or enjoy certain pages or aspects of the Site.

At times, some of the advertisers on our Site and their ad service providers set cookies when you click their advertising banners. While we use cookies in other parts of the Site (as discussed above), cookies received with banner ads are collected by those advertisers and their ad service providers, and we do not have access to that information. The ad company's privacy policy and/or that of its service provider will govern the use of this information and The New York Sun is not responsible for the privacy practices of such ad company.

**Opt Out Procedures**

You have the option to opt out of receiving information from The New York Sun. This opt out messaging will appear at the bottom of every email that is sent out. The New York Sun also gives you the option to remove your information from its database completely. If you no longer wish to take advantage of this Site or to receive any form of direct contact from The New York Sun, whether it is email, discounts, newsletters, or other promotional offers or materials, or wish us to delete your personal information from our data records, contact us at [epaper@nysun.com](mailto:epaper@nysun.com) to cancel your account. The New York Sun is not responsible for removing information from third-party lists or databases of any kind.

Please note that we reserve the right to keep any personal or non-personal information submitted or collected until you delete or modify it or until we choose, for business reasons such as obsolescence, to delete it.

**Reviewing or changing your information**

In order to ensure that the information we maintain is accurate, The New York Sun gives users the option to change or modify their information previously provided. If you would like to change your information currently in our database, please contact us at [epaper@nysun.com](mailto:epaper@nysun.com) The New York Sun is not responsible for updating information contained in third-party lists or databases.

**Protection for Children**

This Site is not intended for users under the age of 18. Furthermore, we have no intention of collecting personally identifiable information from children (i.e., individuals under the age of 13). If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, that child's parent or guardian should contact us at [epaper@nysun.com](mailto:epaper@nysun.com) or send us a letter marked "Privacy � Urgent" at the address below if they would like the information submitted by the child deleted from our database. We will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

**Privacy Precaution Warning**

Please note that no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of the information that you transmit via our online services.

Please note that we reserve the right to access and/or disclose personal information and non-personal information we gather as required by courts or administrative agencies and to the extent required to permit us to investigate suspected fraud, harassment or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, the Site rules or policies, or the rights of third parties or to investigate any suspected conduct which The New York Sun deems improper.

This Site may provide links or references to other web sites. However, we have no control over or responsibility for content on third party sites and transactions that occur therein. The privacy policies and terms and conditions governing this Site may differ significantly from the policies of third party web sites.

**Your Consent**

By using this Site, you accept these terms and consent to our collection, use, disclosure and storage of your personally identifiable and non-personal information as described above. In addition, by using the Site, you also authorize the export of personal information to the USA and its storage and use as specified above when you provide such information to us. Our headquarters is in the USA in New York, New York. This policy and our legal obligations are subject to the laws of New York and the USA, regardless of the location of any user. Any claims or complaints must be filed in the USA in the State of New York.

We may amend our privacy policy, but if we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact us at: [epaper@nysun.com](mailto:epaper@nysun.com).

In addition, our mailing address is:  
The New York Sun  
105 Chambers Street, 2nd Fl  
New York, NY 10007

| 

[New Policy Is Sought in Albany After Report on Silver's Travel](http://www.nysun.com/new-york/new-policy-is-sought-in-albany-after-report/86862/)

---|---|---
